# **Zhi WANG**

Associate Research Fellow
Department of Control Science and Intelligence Engineering
Nanjing University

https://heyuanmingong.github.io

Email: zhiwang@nju.edu.cn

Phone: +86 13160032505

#### **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

My research interests include reinforcement learning (RL) algorithms and their applications in robotics, operations research, and financial technology.

Specifically, I work on how learning algorithms can scale RL agents to dynamic environments (or "open" environments), allowing them to autonomously adapt to the non-stationary task distributions in real-world domains. This includes a wide range of topics such as incremental learning, lifelong learning, transfer learning, and meta-learning.

# **EXPERIENCE**

2022.11-Now Associate Research Fellow, Nanjing University

Department of Control Science and Intelligence Engineering

2019.11–2022.10 Assistant Research Fellow, Nanjing University

Department of Control Science and Intelligence Engineering

2022 Visiting Scholar, Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences

Visiting tutors: Professor Yuanheng Zhu, Dongbin Zhao

2019 Visiting Scholar, University of New South Wales

Visiting tutor: Professor Daoyi Dong

## **EDUCATION**

2015.09-2019.10 Ph.D. City University of Hong Kong

Machine Learning, Department of Systems Engineering and Engineering Management

Supervisor: Professor Han-Xiong Li

2011.09-2015.08 B.E. Nanjing University

Automation, Department of Control and Systems Engineering

## **SELECTED PUBLICATIONS**

- Junyi Wang, **Zhi Wang\***, Huaxiong Li, and Chunlin Chen, "Adaptive noise-based evolutionary reinforcement learning with maximum entropy," *Acta Automatica Sinica*
- Donghan Xie, **Zhi Wang\***, Chunlin Chen, Daoyi Dong, "Depthwise convolution for multi-agent communication with enhanced mean-field approximation," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*
- **Zhi Wang**, Chunlin Chen, and Daoyi Dong, "Lifelong incremental reinforcement learning with online Bayesian inference," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*

- **Zhi Wang**, Chunlin Chen, and Daoyi Dong, "Instance weighted incremental evolution strategies for reinforcement learning in dynamic environments," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*
- **Zhi Wang**, Chunlin Chen, and Daoyi Dong, "A Dirichlet process mixture of robust task models for scalable lifelong reinforcement learning," *IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics*
- Yuanyang Zhu, **Zhi Wang\***, Chunlin Chen, and Daoyi Dong, "Rule-based reinforcement learning for efficient robot navigation with space reduction," *IEEE-ASME Transactions on Mechatronics*
- **Zhi Wang** and Han-Xiong Li, "Dissimilarity analysis-based multimode modeling for complex distributed parameter systems," *IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems*
- 2020 **Zhi Wang**, Han-Xiong Li, and Chunlin Chen, "Incremental reinforcement learning in continuous spaces with policy relaxation and importance weighting," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*
- **Zhi Wang**, Han-Xiong Li, and Chunlin Chen, "Reinforcement learning-based optimal sensor placement for spatiotemporal modeling," *IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics*
- **Zhi Wang**, Chunlin Chen, Han-Xiong Li, Daoyi Dong, and Tzyh-Jong Tarn, "Incremental reinforcement learning with prioritized sweeping for dynamic environments," *IEEE-ASME Transactions on Mechatronics*
- **Zhi Wang** and Han-Xiong Li, "Incremental spatiotemporal learning for online modeling of distributed parameter systems," *IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems*
- **Zhi Wang**, Wei Bi, Yan Wang, and Xiaojiang Liu, "Better fine-tuning via instance weighting for text classification," *AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence*

Note: \*indicates the corresponding author

# **TEACHING**

- <Deep Reinforcement Learning>, mainly for postgraduates, 2019–Now
- <Introduction to Automation>, for undergraduates, 2019–2022
- < Digital Circuits>, for undergraduates, 2022-Now

## **SOCIAL SERVICES**

- Reviewer for leading journals and top conferences
  - IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems
  - IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics
  - IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics
  - IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems
  - IEEE-CAA Journal of Automatica Sinica
  - AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence
- Program Chair and Associate Editor for special sessions of international conferences
  - IEEE Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, 2022
  - IEEE Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, 2021
  - IEEE International Conference on Networking, Sensing, and Control, 2020

### **INVITED TALKS**

• Lifelong reinforcement learning for dynamic environments

- 2022.12, The 4th Distributed Artificial Intelligence (DAI) Conference Inviter: Professor Yan Zheng

- 2022.12, Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences Inviter: Professor Yuanheng Zhu

Yi

- 2022.12, Tongji University Inviter: Professor Peng

• Incremental reinforcement learning for dynamic environments

- 2020.12, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China Inviter: Professor Xiaoting Wang

- 2020.12, University of Science and Technology of China Inviter: Professor Lindong Liu

- 2019.04, University of New South Wales Inviter: Professor Daoyi Dong

• Instructor of summer course "Deep Reinforcement Learning"

- 2022.07, University of Science and Technology of China Inviter: Professor Lindong Liu

# **HONORS AND AWARDS**

• Doctor of Innovation and Entrepreneurship in Jiangsu Province, 2020–2022

• Outstanding Academic Performance Award, City University of Hong Kong, 2018

• Research Tuition Scholarship, City University of Hong Kong, 2018